Gauray Purohit

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

gpgourav27@gmail.com

+917573024785

linkedin.com/in/gaurav-purohit-a4500196

Summary

A dynamic experience in different industries of various verticals, including Telecom, Health Care and IT fields on domestic and international platforms for both B2B and B2C orientation with services like SaaS, CRM, and Team leading experience.

Experience



Customer Success Manager

Nutshell InfoTech

Jan 2022 - Present (10 months +)

Responsible to supervise a cross-functional team dedicated to Customer Success. Work directly with customers to ensure they are getting the most out of a product or service. Act as a liaison between service and sales, incorporating product expertise and customer feedback. Some of the KRA are :-

- * Develop a growth strategy focused both on financial gain and customer satisfaction
- * Customer onboarding, training, and support
- * Arrange business meetings with prospective clients
- * Promote the company's products/services addressing or predicting clients' objectives
- * Provide trustworthy feedback and after-sales support
- * Build long-term relationships with new and existing customers
- * Develop entry level staff into valuable Customer Success Executives



Wordpress Developer

Nutshell InfoTech

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022 (1 year 1 month)

Responsible for designing and implementing websites for clients using the WordPress creation tool. For both front-end and back-end development, including the implementation of themes and plugins. The goal is to create attractive and user-friendly websites according to client specifications, and be profitable.

Web Developer

Freelance

Dec 2019 - Jan 2021 (1 year 2 months)

Being a freelancer I have to get the projects by marketing through Fiverr and other known resources; after getting a project following are the basic responsibilities:

- * Contact the client and get to know as much as possible about the project.
- * Get to know about the needs of the client and about the budget.
- * Prepare an efficient and impressive quote keeping the budget and requirements in the mind.
- * Work closely with the client to come up with the most effective and relevant layout of the website.

- * Register the Domain name and get the Hosting for client.
- * Create databases and start building the website.
- * Complete the Search Engine Optimization.
- * Maintain the websites/project.

Senior Executive - VOIS

Vodafone Global Enterprise

Feb 2019 - Nov 2019 (10 months)

Delivering high-quality customer care services for chat, complaints, and IoT. Offering a range of scaled services at basic, advanced, and complex levels - all focused on enabling powerful customer relationships that drive business success.

Sales Specialist - UK

Vodafone Global Enterprise

Mar 2015 - Feb 2019 (4 years)

Attending and converting potential customers from different verticals of UK market, like Mobile Contracts, SIM Only Contracts, Standalone Mobiles, Broadband Contracts, and other products available in UK market, on chat.

Freelance Web Developer

Digital Marketplace

Oct 2014 - Mar 2015 (6 months)

Working closely with various individuals for different projects and getting part-time work from Fiverr and other such freelance portals.

Medical Record Retrieval - Associate

Mednautix Pvt. Ltd

May 2014 - Sep 2014 (5 months)

Essential Duties and Responsibilities:

- * Make outbound calls to medical facilities to inquire and confirm details about patients' medical records to process insurance.
- * Schedule medical record pickups from medical facility.
- * Checking and verifying the medical records before forwarding to the insurance companies.
- * Forwarding the medical records to the insurance companies.
- * Adding special request orders, override orders for records.
- * Responsible for maintaining monthly record rate, call volume, handle time, logged time and quality scores.

Sales Coach Intern - Operations

Etech Global Services

Nov 2013 - Apr 2014 (6 months)

Manage 5-15 subordinate Team Members who are in direct contact with the customers of a particular campaign. Responsible for

- * The overall direction, coordination, and evaluation of the team.
- * Carry out supervisory responsibilities in accordance with the organization's policies and applicable laws.
- * Directing training of employees; planning, assigning, and directing work; appraising performance; rewarding and disciplining employees; addressing complaints, resolving problems and forwarding them to higher management if required.

Online Chat Representative – Operations

Etech Global Services

Aug 2012 - Nov 2013 (1 year 4 months)

Essential Duties and Responsibilities:

- * Answer and respond to a high volume of chats from customers inquiring about company products/ services, billing, and repair needs.
- * Schedule installation and service appointment for services and use the current billing system to verify customer status, obtain service availability dates and schedule appointments.
- * Handle customer inquiries in a timely, professional manner while maintaining accuracy of details, chat duration and quality customer relations.
- * Educate and consult customers on products to which they do not currently subscribe in order to maximize sales of company products/services.
- * Troubleshoot problems over the chat with customers who are experiencing issues with their service or equipment.
- * Review billing statements with customers and compute costs associated with their subscription in order to resolve discrepancies and to answer questions. Adjust customer-billing statements on the computerized billing system when a service-related problem has occurred. Uses empowerment skills to analyze a situation to resolve issues. This involved issuing additional credit or mailing out promotional coupons to ensure customer satisfaction.
- * Responsible for maintaining subscriber confidentiality related to customer information, along with assisting in the prevention of fraud attempts by non-authorized callers.
- * Responsible for maintaining monthly sales, call volume, handle time, logged time and quality scores.

Metadata Admin Support

Tata Tele Business Services

May 2011 - Sep 2011 (5 months)

Collecting, verifying, arranging and collating the customer application forms from different available sources. Input the collated customers' data on the web-based company portal keeping the security and authenticity. Generate a complete report of the data and forward the same to the head office within the given time.

Education



🍘 Dr. C. V. Raman University, Kota Bilaspur

Bachelor's of Computer Applications Jul 2019 - Aug 2022

Licenses & Certifications

- **The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing** Google Digital Garage PJ6 AFZ 0N3
- in Writing in Plain Language LinkedIn
- Google Ads Display Certification Google Digital Academy (Skillshop)
- Google Analytics for Beginners Google analytics
- Google Analytics Individual Qualification Google Digital Academy (Skillshop)
 Issued Apr 2022 Expires Apr 2023
 110659993
- Google Ads Search certification Google Digital Academy (Skillshop)
 Issued Apr 2022 Expires Apr 2023
 110659930
- **Google Cloud Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure** Google
- **G** Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Core Services Google
- **Essential Google Cloud Infrastructure: Foundation** Google GDQSQMWA9MUC
- Preparing for Google Cloud Certification: Cloud Engineer Specialization Coursera
 MVL62T2PTYVL
- **Creative Certification Exam** Google Issued Sep 2022 Expires Sep 2023
- Google Analytics Certification Google Issued Sep 2022 - Expires Sep 2023
- Internet of Things Hardware Skillsoft 58563985
- Build Responsive Website using HTML5, CSS3, JS And Bootstrap EDUCBA 4-8TLNSRR



Skills

Cross-functional Team Leadership • Team Management • Team Building • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • WordPress Design • WordPress • WooCommerce • HTML • Plain Language • Writing